{\clip(190,219,190,219)\t(0,600,\clip(100,217,280,220))\t(16600,17100,\clip(190,217,190,220))}m 0 0 m 180 1 l 0 1 l 0 0 l 180 0
{\clip(80,220,300,220)\t(0,600,\clip(80,197,300,240))\t(3700,4200,\clip(80,220,300,220))}翻\h译
老佛爷lfy\h\h\h榴莲爱好者\h\h\h\hZoeyJolly
哈哈哈是奇\h\h\h汤包小螺螺\h\h\h\hMasterStormtrooper
{\clip(80,220,300,220)\t(0,600,\clip(80,197,300,240))\t(3700,4200,\clip(80,220,300,220))}校对\h&\h后期
KKKwn\h\h\h\h你以为列
{\clip(80,220,300,220)\t(0,600,\clip(80,197,300,240))\t(3700,4200,\clip(80,220,300,220))}总监
大红
片头推广合作洽谈\h请联系普罗米修斯邮箱\hPLMXS2016@GmaiL.com
当心
Look out.
钓到鳟鱼了
We got a trout.
那是给你的  艾比
That's for you, Abby.
-我呢  -下一条  好吗
- What about me? - Next one. Alright.
嗨
Hi!
你要去哪
Where you goin', huh?
-操  -死小孩
- Fuck! - Damn kid.
他出去了吗
Is he out?
-孩子出去了吗  -你做了什么
- Is the kid out? - What did you do?
走  走  我去开后备箱
Go, go. I'll open the trunk.
把他绑起来
Tie him up!
别他妈的绑蝴蝶结  绑紧点
Not a fuckin' bowtie, tie him tight!
反正他也没知觉了
He can't feel it anyway.
闭嘴
Shut up!
-抓住他  -等等  抓住了  抓住了
- Grab him. - Wait. Got him, got him.
搞定了
Got him.
该死  老兄
Man! Ger, shit.
快点
Come on!
-你再慢一点啊  -你能安静吗
- Take your sweet time there! - Will you be quiet?
好了  我们拍张照  和艾比站在一快
Okay, let's take a picture, um, just go stand with Abby.
去  去  去  站过去靠紧一点
Go, go, go, you go down and stand together really close.
保持微笑  一直看着我  好吗
Keep smiling, look at me the whole time, okay?
保持微笑  好吗
Keep smiling, okay?
艾比  艾比
Abby? Abby!
亲爱的  看镜头
Honey, look at the camera!
笑一笑  好吗  好极了  笑一笑
Big smile, okay? Great, big smile.
克利夫顿山
失踪案
-那是什么  -我的工程师之戒
- What's that? Wow! - My iron ring.
耻辱之戒
是一枚仅仅授予北美顶尖几所大学工程系毕业生的戒指
加拿大魁北克大桥悲剧
垮塌桥梁的钢筋被重铸为一枚枚戒指  提醒每一位工程师的义务与职责
戒指在毕业时授予我们工程师
They give it to the engineers when we graduate.
钢材来自魁北克第一大桥
The iron's from the first Quebec Bridge
那次事故导致13人死亡
that collapsed and killed thirteen people.
-有点恐怖  -这是象征性的
- That's kind of morbid. - It's symbolic.
我想现在用的是不锈钢
I think they use stainless steel now.
铁会让你的手指变黑
Iron turns your fingers black.
大家下午好
Good afternoon, folks.
我们离目的地大约有十分钟车程
We're about ten minutes from our destination
离你第一次看到瀑布大概还有十秒钟
and about ten seconds from your first glimpse of the Falls.
看  在那  就在那
Look, there it is. There it is.
首先请允许我向你表示最深切的哀悼
May I first give you my deepest condolences.
你们的母亲是一股力量
Your mother was a force
但你们应该比任何人都清楚这点
but you guys would know that better than anybody.
我的眼镜呢
Now, where's my glasses?
所以  我签了这个  就好了
So, I just sign this, and it's done?
不  不  我需要你们俩都签字
No, no, no, I need you both to sign it.
她同意了吗
She agreed to this?
这栋楼一文不值
Well, the building's worthless,
要是算上拆掉它的成本更不值钱
it's less than worthless when you count the cost of tearing it down.
但对这块地来说是个公平的价格
But that is a fair price for the land.
查尔斯湖公司
The Charles Lake company?
这不是在竞价
It wasn't exactly a bidding war.
彩虹旅馆对她来说就是一切
The Rainbow was everything to her.
她别无选择  对吧
She wasn't given much of a choice, was she?
我觉得这还不错
This looks good to me.
劳雷  劳雷
Laure? Laure!
拜托  这是我们的遗产
Come on, this is our legacy.
艾比  你是认真的吗
Abby, are you serious?
协议上说我们有六个星期
The agreement says we have six weeks.
-拜托  我们得试试  -试
- Come on, we have to try. - Try?
试什么  彩虹吗
Try what? The -- the Rainbow?
那是妈妈想要的
It's what mom would want.
妈妈安排了你刚谈完的那笔买卖
Mom arranged the sale that you just walked out on.
那地方是个垃圾场  艾比  妓女都不会要
The place is a dump, Abby, hookers wouldn't even use it.
他们会把它改成操蛋的夜光
They're gonna turn it into a fucking glow-in-the-dark
迷你高尔夫什么的
mini-golf, or something.
很好
Good.
我们在那里长大
We grew up there!
是啊  我们中有一个长大了
Yeah, one of us grew up.
彩虹
♪ 另一场演出即将结束 ♪
♪ Another show is closing ♪
♪ 熄灭灯光 ♪
♪ Out goes the lights ♪
♪ 收拾好衣服来见我 ♪
♪ Pack up the clothes and see me ♪
♪ 当我们旅行去 ♪
♪ While we travel to ♪
♪ 另一个城镇 ♪
♪ Another town ♪
♪ 当你是明星时 ♪
♪ No time to look for romance ♪
♪ 就没时间浪漫了 ♪
♪ When you're the star.. ♪
天哪  这东西不
Jesus, this thing is not..
老兄  我觉得  点唱机坏了
Hey, man, I think the, uh, the jukebox is broken.
抱歉
Sorry.
但是  牌子上写着
Uh, but, uh, the sign said that --
牌子上写着免费  没写着有用
Sign says it's free, doesn't say it works.
该死
Well, shit.
你要知道  鬼屋其实并不闹鬼
Just so you know, the haunted houses aren't actually haunted.
而游乐场其实也不好玩
And the fun houses aren't actually fun.
不错  我喜欢
Ha-ha. Nice one, I like that.
省着钱吧  伙计
Just saving you money, dude
路过吗
Passing through?
来找工作
Here for a job.
所以  我猜  你是本地人
So, I guess, uh, I guess, you're a local?
我在这长大
I grew up here.
也就是说你是本地人
That means you're a local.
我在这长大
I grew up here.
你在这长大
You grew up here.
好吧  好吧  我在这里长大的小姐
Well, okay, well, Miss I-Grew-Up-Here
我以为这整个地方
I thought that this whole place
应该像维加斯一样  但并不是
was supposed to be like Vegas, and it's not.
现在是淡季
Well, it's the low season.
他们甚至调小了瀑布
They even turn down the Falls.
怎么把尼亚加拉瀑布调小的
How do you turn Niagara Falls down?
用一系列水闸  把水引到发电厂
It's a series of locks, divert the water to the power plant.
我在水电站做硕士实习
I'm doing my Master's on the hydro dam.
想弄到那个铁戒指
Trying to get that iron ring.
这是工程界的事
It's an engineering thing.
金属是从一座桥上运来的
The metal's from a -- a bridge
那座桥害死了很多人
that killed a bunch of people.
这有点恐怖  但有象征性
It's morbid, but...symbolic.
真的吗  认真的吗
Is that true, seriously?
查一下
Hm, look it up.
你知道我会怎么做吗
You know what I'd do?
我会整个弄干
I'd dry the whole thing up.
就像当年美国人一样
Like the Americans did back in the day.
这是个不错的小镇
This is a nice town.
但那东西让人抓狂
But that thing drives people crazy.
只是一堆水从石头上落下
It's just a bunch of water falling over some rocks.
你想再来一杯吗
Do you want another one?
当然
Sure.
网站上可不是这样的
Well, it's not exactly how it looks on the website.
等等
Wait.
我喜欢
Woo! I like that.
-是啊  -我喜欢
- Yeah. - I like that.
可以
Okay.
我是处女
I'm a virgin.
你说什么
What did you say?
没有什么
Nothing.
等等  等等  等等  你
Wait, wait, wait, wait, did you..
刚说你是处女
just say you're a virgin?
不
No.
你不是处女
You're not a virgin, there's, uh..
你只是
You just, uh..
你刚在酒吧接了个陌生人
You just picked up a stranger in a bar.
那是怎么回事
So, uh, what's up with that, huh?
在听吗
Hello?
妈的  真他妈奇怪
Fuck, weird as fuck!
抱歉  没有空房
Uh, sorry, no vacancy.
你是艾比吗
Are you Abby?
艾比  查理
Abby, Charlie.
我是查尔斯湖公司的
I'm with CLC.
不  听着  我不是来惹麻烦的
No, look, I'm not here to start any trouble.
我们也是家族企业  我明白
We're a family business, too, I understand
你所经历的  我们
what you're going through, we, uh..
几年前我父亲去世了
lost my father a few years back, it was, uh..
节哀顺便
Condolences.
当我们听到你妈妈的消息时我真的很惊讶
I was actually surprised to hear from your mother when we did.
经营这样的地方需要点勇气
Takes a certain kind of moxie to run a place like this.
偷窃一个脆弱的寡妇需要什么代价呢
What does it take to pilfer it from a vulnerable widow?
我只想知道你是否改变主意了
I just want you to know if you do change your mind..
没有恶意
No hard feelings.
真的
Really.
很高兴见到你  艾比
Pleasure to meet you, Abby.
-谢谢  -为什么
- Thanks. - For what?
-晚餐  -这是他的主意
- Dinner. - It was his idea.
所以  马库斯  你在赌场做什么
So, Marcus, what do you do at the casino?
不会比你姐姐更高档的了
Well, nothing fancy like your sister.
他是我们的第一道防线
He's our first line of defense.
告诉她你在找什么  很科幻
Tell her what you look for. It's very scientific.
好吧  有一种艺术
Okay, well, there is a certain art to it.
快速眨眼  把物体放在
Rapid blinking, um, placing objects
他们和发牌人之间
between themselves and the dealer
脚指向出口
uh, feet pointed towards an exit.
好吧  口头上  像是确定关系的语言
Well, verbally, it's stuff like, um, formalized language.
我是说  我没有性关系
I mean, like, uh, I did not have sexual relations..
嗨  鱼饵
Hi. Fishing lures.
今天只有鱼饵
Just fishing lures today.
但我可以告诉你  我找到了其他的东西
But I have found other things, I can tell you.
比如什么
Like what?
武器  手表  结婚戒指
Oh, firearms, watches, wedding rings.
那通常会是一个大动作
That one's usually a grand gesture!
从瀑布那落下的最终会
Everything that goes over the Falls ends up..
流过这个大盆地
flowing through this big basin here.
有时候我很走运
Sometimes I get lucky.
沃尔特  很高兴认识你
Walter. Nice to meet you.
-很高兴认识你  -是啊
- Nice to meet you. - Yeah.
城外来的
Out of town?
-温哥华  -好远啊
- Vancouver. - Oh, that's -- that's far away.
你  你找对人了
Well, you've -- you've come to the right guy.
是啊  我  我算是个城市历史学家
Yeah, I -- I'm -- I'm sort of the town historian.
-你喜欢播客吗  -当然
- You like podcasts? - Uh, sure.
那叫  《瀑布之上》
Yeah, it's called "Over the Falls."
这些地方有很多历史
Lot of history around these parts.
太多的历史了
An awful lot of history.
-我猜也是  -是啊
- I bet. - Yeah, well.
记得
Uh, remember..
给播客打分评论
rate and review the -- the podcast.
有助于我们的排名
It -- it helps our rankings.
艾比  但是  你怎么上来的
Abby.. But, how'd you get up here?
我自有办法
I'm resourceful.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
来看你上班  你是我妹妹
Visiting you at work, because you're my sister.
你不能到这来
You can't be here.
所以这就是天眼
So this is the eye in the sky.
我只是个主管  别看来看去了
I'm just a supervisor, stop stalling.
还记得我们小时候吗
Remember back when we were kids?
我不知道怎么回答你
I don't quite know how to answer that.
还记得我以前说过的独眼男孩吗
Remember I used to talk about the one-eyed boy?
我记得你说过好多事情
I remember you telling me about a lot of things.
他只有一只眼睛
He had one eye.
好吧  我发现了一张照片
Okay, I found a picture.
你说之前  先听我说
Before you say anything, just hear me out --
我不可以跟你聊  现在是工作时间
I can't do this right now, at my work.
那什么时候
When then?
频道五  接入频道五
Channel five. Come in, channel five.
监控中心收到  请说
Yeah, surveillance, go ahead.
他们在不同的频道  这个不能合并
They're on separate channels, they can't be consolidated.
我五点可以休息一会
I have a break at five.
如果你想跟正常人一样和妹妹聊天
If you want to visit your sister like a regular person,
可以那个时候到大厅来找我
you can do it then.. ...in the lobby.
嘿  我们在这做什么
Hey, um, what are we doing here?
对了  谢谢你送我过来
Thanks for the lift, by the way.
如果让你掺和这事  劳雷会杀了我的
Laure would kill me if I got you involved.
听着  艾比
Look, Abby, um..
劳雷告诉我一些事情
...Laure has told me some...things.
艾比 韦斯特
Abby West!
有什么可以帮你  韦斯特小姐
So, how can I help you, Miss West?
我要举报一起绑架案
I want to report a kidnapping.
-绑架案  -是的
- A kidnapping? - Yeah.
一个男孩在皇后镇码头附近被绑
A boy near the Queenston docks.
1994年感恩节周末
Thanksgiving weekend, 1994.
1994年
1994?
是的
Yeah.
-你亲眼看到了  -是的
- You witnessed this? - Yeah.
-你那时候多大  -七岁
- How old were you? - Seven.
那时候你才七岁
You were seven, hm.
是的 我发现一张照片
I found a picture,
很肯定是这些人绑走了他
pretty surethose are the people that took him.
-那个男孩多大  -比我大些  12或者13岁
- How old was the boy? - Older than me. Maybe 12, 13.
为什么不是你父母来举报
Why didn't your parents report it?
他们没有看到  我是唯一一个目击证人
They didn't see it, I was the only one around.
你为什么不告诉他们
Why didn't you tell them?
我觉得我应该说了
Well, I think I did.
好吧  我告诉我妹妹  但她说我是个骗子
Well, I told my sister, but she called me a liar.
好吧  说完了吗
Well, yeah, is that it?
-说完了  -谢谢你过来
- Yeah. - Thank you for coming in.
就这样吗
That's it?
不好意思
I'm sorry, you --
有一个儿童绑架案的目击证人过来找你
you have an eyewitness coming forward about a child abduction
你却一个字都没有记录
and you're not even writing anything down.
根据我的经验  我不信任你朋友
Based on my experience, I -- I don't trust your friend.
-她是我妻姐  -你结婚了
- She's my sister-in-law. - You're married?
她是我老婆的姐姐  有什么问题吗
She's my wife's sister! What is going on here?
他新来的
He's new.
第一周在这工作  对吗
First week on the job, right?
还适应吗
Fitting in?
-目前还可以  -肯定还可以
- So far. - Must be.
就凭直觉能将目击证人拒之门外
Turning away a witness on a hunch?
好吧  算了  等等
Hm, okay. Well, wait here.
-你认识他  -不
- You know him? - No.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey!
失踪
艾比
Abby!
什么
What?
这不是你瞎编的故事之一吧
This isn't one of your fantastical stories, is it?
是劳雷这么说的吗
Is that what Laure calls them?
-所以呢  -没有
- So? - No.
没有吗
No?
正在调查和结案的男孩失踪案
There are no open or closed cases of a missing boy
没有符合该日期和描述的
that match your date or description.
记得走的时候签个名
So remember to sign yourselves out when you leave.
我就是不喜欢这种装模作样的人  你知道吗
I just didn't like the smugness, you know?
这种态度
The attitude.
你做的事肯定是对的
You absolutely did the right thing.
我的意思是  你只是  你也不知道
I mean, you just, you never know.
也许你  只是在报纸上看到什么
Heck, maybe you -- you saw something in the papers
然后记在了脑子里
and you just combined it in your head..
本地名人组合的儿子假定死亡
Alex Moulin
神奇穆兰
最棒和最勇敢的人总是被尼亚加拉大瀑布吸引
The best and the bravest have always been drawn to Niagara Falls.
可能是想借此机会在世界最大的舞台上
Called perhaps by the chance to showcase
展示他们非凡的技能
their extraordinary skills on the world's largest stage.
他们的名字成为了传奇
Their names have become legend.
但是只有一个名字能使
But only one name
每年数百万来此的游客振奋
electrifies the millions who flock to the Falls every year.
只有一个名字
Only one name rings out above
比瀑布的咆哮声和雷鸣声还要响亮
the roar and thunder of the water.
神奇穆兰
The Magnificent Moulins
数年以来  我们一直在找一个机会进驻
Well, for several years, we've been looking for an entry point
晚餐剧院的市场
into the dinner theatre market.
现在已经找到了
Now that search is over.
我们的观众一定会喜欢
Our audiences will absolutely love --
是  我们真的很感激莱克先生
Yeah, we -- we -- we're truly, uh, indebted to Mr. Lake, yeah.
他的启发成就了我们最好的表演
He inspired us to create our greatest trick yet.
都是他的功劳
It's because of him.
-全是他的功劳  -是的
- It's because of him. - Yeah, and..
但是他们最棒的表演
But their greatest trick
没有特殊助手的帮忙无法完成
wouldn't be possible without the help of a very special assistant.
她就是我们的
She is our -- -
老虎就是我们的家人
Tigers are family to us.
他们就像是  我们的合作伙伴
They're like, um, collaborators.
这是我们魔术的一个巨大的进步
It's really a great evolution of our magic.
是的
Yeah.
皮夹克不适合我
The leather jacket was a bad choice.
我祖父最开始建这房子
You know, my grandad originally built
是要自己住的
this as a private residence.
很自负  对吧
Priggish, right?
但是战后它也被用做
But it was also used as a convalescent hospital
空军康复医院
by the Air Force after the war.
我还记得学校组织的实地考察
I remember the school field trip.
肯定是在他们确认了我们的历史地位以后
Well, that must have been after they got our historic status.
爱德华八世还没上位时坐过这凳子
But the future King Edward VIII sat in this very chair.
好酷
Cool.
他是希特勒的朋友  对吗
He was friends with Hitler, right?
我来这是为了彩虹旅馆
I'm here about the Rainbow.
你打算怎么处理
What were you gonna do with it?
我不应该说的  但是
Uh, I probably shouldn't say, but, uh..
改造成黑夜之光彩弹球迷宫  开个玩笑
Glow-in-the-dark paintball maze. Killer, right?
玩笑啊
Killer.
听着  我认识市政厅一些人
Look, I -- I know the folks down at City Hall.
或许我们可以挂块牌子在上面注明
Maybe we could get a -- a plaque put up.
前身是彩虹旅馆
The former site of the historic Rainbow Inn.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
那工作呢
What about a job?
什么工作
A job?
你是镇上最大的老板
You're the biggest employer in town.
如果我没有酒店了
If I lose my motel
我也需要有份差事
I'm going to need something to do.
好的  你想要什么呢
Okay, uh, what did you have in mind?
好吧  我觉得我能习惯在这里工作
Well, I could get used to working in a place like this.
什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是我们可以商量
Um, well, it means that we can discuss it.
那就好
Great.
但是  现在  我还要去见我的家人  所以
But, right now, I have a date with my family, so..
是去镇上吗
Is it in town?
为什么这么问
Why?
记得他们吗
Remember them?
我小时候  他们经常在山上演出
They used to have a show on the hill when I was a kid.
他们曾经是我们的骄傲
They used to be our crown jewel.
-没有吧  -是的
- No! - Oh, yeah.
好吧  看起来他们好像没落了
Well, it seems like they crossed over to the dark side.
是的  曾经很重要  很重要
Yeah, it was a major, major..
你可能还是太小了
You're probably too young.
他们儿子  是在峡谷被发现的
Their son, they found him in the gorge.
-不可能  -是自杀
- No shit! - Yeah, suicide.
是贝尔家族发现的他
The Bells found him.
至少他还有全尸
At least what was left of him.
他们确定是自杀吗
Are they sure it was a suicide?
你真的很好奇
You've got a curious streak, huh?
是  我可是新闻学校毕业的
Well, journalism school.
难怪
Oh, yeah.
好吧  我记得  这个孩子老是遇到麻烦
Well, from what I remember, the kid was, uh, troubled.
-你认识他吗  -认识
- And you knew him? - Yeah, I did.
甚至曾经保护过他  所以
Even took him under my wing, so..
所以穆兰夫妇就收拾家当
So the Moulins just packed up..
去河对面演出吗
...took their show across the river?
嗯  大概是这样
Yeah, something like that.
{\move(250,150,235,120)\fs20\t(1000,8000,\fs10)\blur0\t(5000,8000,\blur3)\bord0\shad0}贝尔斯
乐队
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
你从没回来过
You never came back.
你这些天一直待这吗
Have you been staying here?
-没  -没有吗
- No. - No?
我记得那个独眼男孩
I remember the one-eyed boy.
你记得
You do?
我记得你跟我说过一些绑架的事情
I remember you telling me about some kidnapping, yeah.
我还记得恐龙骨头
I also remember the fossil bones
恩里克·伊格莱西亚斯  还有监狱的来信
Enrique Iglesias, the prison letters.
你知道我在说什么吗
You see where I'm going?
什么
What?
现在你还对警察撒谎
Now you're lying to the cops.
我没有说谎
I didn't lie.
还把我丈夫拖下水  你疯了吗
And you dragged my husband into this, are you crazy?
这是他的主意
It was his idea.
是  我肯定他也觉得是他的主意
Yeah, I'm sure he thought it was.
劳雷  我没有撒谎
Laure! I'm not lying.
只要  只要给我两分钟
Just -- just give me two minutes.
两分钟就行  如果之后你还觉得我在胡扯
Two minutes, after that if you still think it's bullshit..
我就放弃
...I'll drop it.
好了  坐下吧
Okay, sit down.
劳雷
Laure.
你好啊
Hello.
你对神奇穆兰了解多少
What do you know about the Magnificent Moulins?
我知道的不多
I don't know,
只有老虎  烟雾机  和老掉牙的魔术
tigers and smoke machines and corny magic tricks.
好  这篇文章  是1994年10月13号的
Okay, this article, dated October 13th, 1994
上面宣布亚亚历克斯·穆兰  组合的独生子
states that Alex Moulin, the Duo's only child
是自杀身亡
was declared dead by suicide.
据说他跳进了峡谷
He allegedly jumped into the gorge.
然而  他们一直没发现他的尸体
However, they never recovered his body.
那他们怎么知道是自杀的
So, how'd they know it was suicide?
也许警察没有把所有消息透露给媒体
Probably the police didn't release everything to the press.
好吧
Okay, fine.
还记得这个吗
Now remember this?
这是1994年感恩节前一天拍的
That was the day before Thanksgiving, 1994.
文章出版的前四天拍的
Four days before the article came out.
如果你不相信我  这有时间标记
It's date-stamped, if you don't believe me.
你说你记得我告诉过你
You said yourself you remember me telling you
那天发生过绑架的事情
about a kidnapping that day.
一个男孩  很可能是亚历克斯
A boy, possibly like Alex.
除了那张  妈妈那天还拍了几十张照片
Besides that picture, mum took dozens of photos that day.
这是其中一张
This being one of them.
现在看这儿
Now watch this.
这是我在图书馆找到的
I found this at the library.
这是亚历克斯死亡前两年
It's a film about the Moulins
拍的关于穆兰夫妇的纪录片
made two years before Alex's death.
这里
There.
看看那个黑色头发的女人
Look at that woman with the black hair.
再看看这张照片
Now, look at this picture.
劳雷  你说我是不是在骗人
Laure, tell me I'm lying.
靠
Shit.
我找到了些信息
Okay, I found something.
"大家称之为贝尔潜游一族
"Collectively known as the Diving Bells.
贝尔家族是当地的冒险及救援家庭
The Bells were a local family of daredevils and rescuers.
在过去的半个世纪里
Pulled over two hundred bodies from the gorge
从峡谷里拖出了两百多具尸体"
in the last half century."
"最棒的以及最勇敢的"
"The best and the bravest."
这看起来像多代传承的事
Looks like it was a multi-generational thing.
1977年因为一个操作失误
One died in 1977, Thomas Bell
家庭其中一员  托马斯·贝尔逝世
a stunt gone wrong.
他留下了4个孩子
He left four children,
他们大多数还在家族企业里
most of them still in the family business
凯瑟琳  沃尔特  斯科特和托尼
Catherine, Walter, Scott and Tony.
郊区有个游乐场以他们命名
There's a playground named after them uptown --
等下  刚那句
Wait, go back.
那些孩子  他们叫什么名字
The kids, what were their names?
"凯瑟琳  沃尔特  斯科特和托尼"
"Catherine, Walter, Scott and Tony."
欢迎收听《瀑布之上》
Ndio, kwe and yineh to the "Over The Falls" podcast
来自位于尼亚加拉大瀑布
recorded live from the hangar deck
航母甲板上的现场录音
of Niagara Falls
就在飞碟餐厅哦
only Flying Saucer.
飞碟餐厅
我是沃尔特·贝尔
I'm Walter Bell,
各位  就如劳伦斯·威尔克所说
and, folks, as Lawrence Welk would say
美国著名音乐家  乐队指挥家和电视主持人
"能来到这里  我荣幸至极"
"It's wonderful, wonderful to be here."
我们今天为您准备了顶级的节目
We've got a triple A gem of a show for you today.
外星生命体正在接近
Alien lifeform approaching.
你们好  地球人
Greetings, earthlings.
-两位吗  -是的
- For two? - Yeah.
请跟我来
Follow me.
在一个普朗克之内回来
Back in a chronon.
科学术语
指能量频率振动的最短时间单位
接下来怎样
So, what now?
他可能在里面办公室
Maybe he's in the back.
艾比
Abby!
干嘛
What?
亲爱的  女厕在楼下  左边
Ladies room is downstairs, honey, on the left.
-谢谢了  -要点些什么呢亲爱的
- Thanks. - Something for you, hon?
找个还算安静的落脚点
...although maybe find a halfway peaceful spot
在瀑布脚下某处
below the Falls
成为生命开始又结束的地方
where you can spawn and die.
这是一个难以想象的艰难过程
It's a hard thing for any of us to imagine
但正因如此才让本地区的鲑鱼
but it's what makes the salmon in this region
成为了非常难得的美味佳肴
so hard to catch and such a fine, rare treat to eat!
位于伦迪路的爱尔维欧海鲜餐厅
El Viejo Seafood on Lundy's Lane has a half-price special
每周二推出半价帝王鲑和银三文鱼
on king and coho salmon every Tuesday.
你要问我对此的评价
And if you ask me,
这可是值得逆流而上的大特惠
that's a deal worth swimming upstream for.
鲑鱼在繁殖季节逆流而上产卵
我是沃尔特·贝尔
I'm Walter Bell,
这里是《瀑布之上》
this is "Over the Falls"
我们下期再见
and until next time, eskonyen.
你好  上次那个温哥华吗
Hey! Vancouver?
亚历克斯·穆兰
Alex Moulin.
把门关上
Close the door.
-你是谁  -我只是个目击事情经过的人
- What are you? - I'm just someone who saw it.
什么意思  目击什么了
What do you mean, saw it? Saw what?
我目睹他们带走了亚历克斯
Saw them take him.
-那个时候你才  -那时候我7岁
- Oh, you would've been -- - I was seven!
事情发生时候我就在现场  我有证据
I was there when it happened, and I have proof.
-温哥华人  -不  我是本地人
- Vancouver - No, I'm, I'm a local.
知道彩虹旅馆吧
The Rainbow Inn.
回去餐厅点点东西
Go back and order something.
用完餐以后往东走两条街
Eat, then walk two blocks East and
找一辆蓝色的丰田
look for a blue Toyota.
一个人过来
And come alone.
艾比  我们得谈谈
Abby, we need to talk about some things.
谈什么
Like what?
你不相信我
You don't trust me.
我相信你不会烧了我的房子
I trust you not to set my house on fire.
可我总是觉得你不和我说真话
I don't always feel like you're telling me the truth.
行吧  劳雷  你说我该怎么做
Alright, Laure, what can I do? You tell me?
好
Alright.
在多伦多的时候究竟发生了什么
What happened in Toronto?
妈妈一直不告诉我
Mum wouldn't tell me.
什么都没有
Nothing happened. I --
艾比  请说实话
Abby, the truth. Please.
我当时是个自由职业者
I was freelancing.
事实上混得还挺不错
Doing pretty well, actually,
然后我还遇到了个男的
and I met a guy.
人挺不错的
A really nice guy.
他叫什么名字
What was his name?
丹尼尔
Daniel.
我们都很认真  进展也非常快
Things got pretty serious, fast.
后来
And..
我就开始撒谎  越撒越多
...I started telling lies and then more lies.
最后导致一切都离我而去
It all just got away from me..
一直都是这样的结果
...as it always does.
所有事都变得很糟糕
Everything turned to shit.
所以我就把自己关在一个地方
So, I checked myself into a place
关了几个星期
for a couple of weeks
然后咱妈的心脏病就发作了
and...then mum had her heart attack.
没了
That's it.
谢谢
Thank you.
我知道你不容易
I know that wasn't easy.
好吧好吧
Yeah, yeah.
我真的得走了
Oof! I really gotta go.
下次见吧
I'll see you?
我看见这两个人强迫亚历克斯
I saw those two people force Alex
上了他们的车
into the trunk of their car,
就在我们第一次见的地方
right where we first met.
-你认识他们吗  -不
- Do you know them? - No.
打开这个
Open this.
一个带血的帽子
A bloody cap.
一个鞋子
One shoe.
这些是我找到的
That's what I found.
就只有这些
All I found.
这看起来像自杀吗
Does that say suicide to you?
你怎么得到这些文件的
How did you get this?
查尔斯二世再怎么样也不能一手遮天
Not every bluecoat was in Charles II's pocket.
查尔斯·雷克二世吗
Charles Lake II?
你都不听播客的吗
Didn't you listen to the podcast?
我意思是
I mean..
抱歉  我意思是亚历克斯还只是个孩子
I'm sorry. I mean, Alex was just a kid.
他和查尔斯·雷克二世能有什么联系呢
What did he have to do with Charles Lake II?
没有
Nothing.
这放查尔斯三世身上也一样说不通
The same can't be said for Charles III.
查理
Charlie?
他对亚历克斯有特别的兴趣
He took a special interest in Alex.
你知道我什么意思吗
You catch my drift?
你别被他那个好孩子的外表蒙骗了
No, don't let that bon enfant routine fool you.
原谅并掩盖查理的过失
Forgiving Charlie his trespasses
对于查尔斯湖公司来说就是家常便饭
was a regular cottage industry at CLC.
你怎么知道这些事的
How do you know this?
你查一下唐尼·梅森
Look up Donnie Mason.
就在亚历克斯事件的两年前
Two years before Alex.
如我所说  这种事不是第一次了
Like I said, it's not the first time.
也可能不是最后一次
Probably won't be the last.
还有穆兰夫妇
And the Moulins?
他们肯定知道这事
They must've known something was going on.
那两只彩色鸡吗  我可不这么认为
Those two cockatiels? I don't think so.
你自己想想  对谁有益[拉丁语]
Ask yourself, cui prodest?
谁受益呢
Who profits?
亚历克斯死后  穆兰夫妇就不再表演了
After losing Alex, the Moulins stopped performing.
这相当于他们的解雇通知单
They got their pink slip.
与此同时  公司还有他们的变态王子
Meanwhile, CLC and their pervert prince
继续称雄
continued to rule the roost.
我一直都清楚他们的动机
I've always had the motive.
而现在  你有手段和机会了
Now, here's the means and the opportunity.
彻查下去
Track 'em down.
你有可能会调查出整个事情的原委
You might be able to complete the picture.
这些你留着吧
You keep it.
可能你运气比我好呢
Maybe you'll have better luck than I did.
"沃尔特·贝尔坚信亚历克斯·穆兰没有自杀
而是被杀人灭口从而掩盖更大的阴谋"
"别相信这个疯子的话"
你知道人从峡谷掉下直达
Do you know what happens when a body hits the water
谷底水面上会变成什么样
at the bottom of the gorge?
就像生吞一颗点燃的炸弹
Think swallowing a live grenade.
而后你要找的不是尸体了
It's no longer a body you're looking for
而是肉块碎末
but pieces of a body.
那么  是什么让
So, what makes the
亚历克斯·穆兰这个案件这么特别呢
Alex Moulin case so special?
在此之前有个名为唐尼·梅森的男孩
Well, here was a boy, just like Donnie Mason before him
也是从峡谷纵身一跃
who we're told leaped into the mighty gorge
然后就永远消失了
and vanished forever.
朋友们  我在尼亚加拉中
Friends, I've fished corpses out of the Niagara
贝尔潜游一族
冒险和搜救队
捞尸体捞了30年  所以我有资格告诉你
for thirty years, so I can tell you
这里面有点不为人知的猫腻
there's always a piece of something.
记住我说的话
Take it from me..
这绝对不是自杀
...this was no suicide.
男孩的死亡当局判定为自杀
Donnie Mason
查理·莱克的野蛮
The savagery of the first Charles Lake
Charles Lake Company
持续75年
为克利夫顿山建造快乐
都是有据可查的
is well-documented.
而他的儿子  查尔斯二世
And his son, Charles II
完全传承了老子
well, he learned from the best.
查尔斯·雷克二世  富有争议的大亨  享年71
但到查尔斯三世时
But Charles III
查理·雷克三世准备继承家业
他的目光却完全转移在了别的事情上
had his eyes on something else entirely.
师徒计划深受欢迎
对他们这么野蛮的家族而言
Something depraved,
他做的事更为恶劣
even by his family's standards.
在他盯上亚历克斯时候
As soon as he set his sights on Alex
这个小男孩便消失无踪了
that boy was as good as gone.
Alex
Moulin
Donnie
Mason
我决定卖给你了
I'm here to sell.
你该不会想要
You're not going to ask for shares
股份什么的吧
or something now, are you?
我才不是过来谈判的
I'm not here to negotiate.
知道吗  一般都是通过律师走这些程序
You know, this usually goes through the lawyers.
律师已经帮我们把合同写好了
Well, I'm guessing they wrote it.
现在根本不需要他们了
So, I don't see why we need them.
每页都签上你名字
Signed on every page.
行  完美
Well, this is excellent.
完美
Excellent.
这些照片挺不错
This is impressive.
对啊  墙上都是满满的回忆
Yeah. A lot of great memories up there.
"Bm"
"Bm."
这边这个是我最喜欢的
My favorite...right here.
拉什乐队  他们在我18岁生日时演唱过
Rush. They performed for my 18th birthday.
加拿大的前卫摇滚团体
那这个呢
What about this one?
这是在亚历克斯消失之前拍的吧
This must have been before Alex disappeared.
醉翁之意不在酒啊
That's what this is?
我有求知欲
I have a curious streak.
我给你点建议
Little bit of advice.
你最好离这些
I would stay away from
有被害妄想症的疯子远一点
tinfoil hat-wearing crazies in this town.
干点其他正事吧
You can do a lot better than that.
你在回避问题
You're avoiding the question.
听着  你觉得你好像知道些什么
Look, whatever you think you know..
相信我  你什么都不知道
...trust me, you don't know anything.
Bm
Bm...
Bev Mole
艾比
Abby!
糟了
Shit!
给我出来  艾比
Come on out, Abby!
妈的
Shit!
开膛手杰克和泰德·邦迪
Jack the Ripper and Ted Bundy.
两人均为美国史上著名连环杀手
泰德为《沉默的羔羊》人物原型
请让一下  让一下
Excuse me, please.. Excuse me.
不好意思  请让开
Excuse me. No. Excuse me.
抱歉  拜托
Excuse me, please.
等等  你还没买票
Hey, you have to buy a ticket.
好吧  给你
Okay, here.
艾比
Abby.
艾比  艾比  艾比
Abby, Abby, Abby.
隐形墨水  你在逗我吗
Disappearing ink, really?
你去的那家恶作剧商店是我的产业
You know I own the gag shop where you bought it.
别说我没告诉你  整个镇子都是我的
So, in case you haven't figured it out, I own this town.
等我搞定了你  沃尔特这个疯子
And when I'm done with you, Walter and all his crazies
和你的狗屁小旅馆
and your shitty little motel,
场面一定很好笑
it's gonna be hilarious.
所以  如果你想玩  我就陪陪你
So, if it's games you want to play with me, we can play
毕竟赢你只是小菜一碟
'cause this is really, really easy for me.
首先  一张票十二美元  我给了二十
Okay, first of all, a ticket is twelve dollars, I paid twenty.
其次  我是查尔斯湖公司的新联络员
And second of all, I'm the new liaison at CLC.
还没上任  不信你问查理
Soon to be. Ask Charlie.
就是莱克先生打电话投诉的
Mr. Lake's the one who called in the complaint.
这只是工作上的误会
It's just a workplace misunderstanding.
我会跟他解释的
I'll talk to him.
查尔斯湖公司的联络员是什么  韦斯特小姐
What exactly does a liaison for CLC do, Miss West?
和其他联络员一样  自己查查吧
What does any liaison do. Look it up.
听着女士  乖乖远离查尔斯湖公司的财产
Listen, ma'am, just stay away from CLC properties.
最好离莱克先生也远点
And I'd stay away from Mr. Lake altogether.
虽然这次他不追究你的责任
He didn't press charges this time
但你肯定没得到那份工作
but it's probably safe to say you didn't get the job.
再见  韦斯特小姐
Have a good night, Miss West.
-你好艾比  -你好
- Hey, Abby. - Hey.
夜班吗
Graveyard shift?
是的
Yeah.
所以
So..
我就知道
I knew it!
贝弗·摩尔1996年被列入禁赌名单
Bev Mole banned from the casino in 1996.
就是她
That's her.
你怎么知道她在赌场系统里
How did you know she'd be in our system?
我猜的
A lucky guess.
有个叫贝弗·摩尔的人1995年6月中了彩票
A Bev Mole won the lottery in June 1995.
她买了两百张
Bought 200 tickets.
除了赌鬼谁会买这么多
Who buys 200 tickets?
还有  看这个
Also, read that.
"这个好消息来得正是时候
"The good news couldn't have come at a better time.
"去年10月有人入室行窃  虽然没得逞
"During a botched home invasion last October
"摩尔的丈夫格里却被暴力袭击
"Mole's husband, Gerry, was violently assaulted
导致腰部以下瘫痪"  10月吗
paralyzing him from the waist down.." October?
入室行窃可能是假的
Maybe it was a double-cross.
你们背着我玩什么呢
You guys having fun without me?
这是绑架案的线索吗
Is this about that kidnapping?
尼亚加拉瀑布赌场
注      意
禁赌人员
对不起  您所拨打的电话无法接通
We're sorry, your call cannot be completed as dialed.
更多帮助请致电运营商
Call your operator to help you.
运营商接听  我能为您做什么
Operator. How can I help you?
你好  我想联系我的婶婶
Uh, hi, I've been trying to reach my aunt
但她换电话号码了
but her number isn't in service anymore.
你能帮我接通她的新号码吗
Could you put me through to the new one?
名字和旧号码是
Name and previous number?
贝弗莉·摩尔
Uh, Beverly Mole.
9-0-5-555-0-1-7-3
9-0-5-555-0-1-7-3.
请稍等
Please hold.
喂
Hello?
是贝弗莉·摩尔吗
Uh...is this Beverly Mole?
你是谁
Who's asking?
你好摩尔小姐
Uh, hi, Miss Mole.
我是尼亚加拉瀑布赌场的客服
I'm from Customer Care at the Niagara Falls Casino.
-好吧  -是的  是的
- Okay. - Uh, yeah, yeah.
我们发现  你有段时间没来玩了
We noticed, uh, you haven't played with us in a while.
我们想吸引你回来
We wanted to try and lure you back.
我们发现你的账户禁用异常
Uh, we noticed there was an improper ban on your account..
我们愿意提供一百美元赌资和免费住宿
...and we'd like to give you a $100 credit and a room.
你愿意来吗
What do you think?
我要做些什么
What do I have to do?
什么也不用  告诉我你哪天来就行
Nothing at all, just let me know when you'd like to redeem it
我来安排
and I'll process it.
周五
Friday.
-本周五吗  -是的
- This Friday? - Yeah.
没问题
Of course.
有家舒适的小旅馆和我们合作
There's a great little place we partner with.
♪ 尽管你警告过我 ♪
♪ Though you warned me not to drive ♪
♪ 别再来你家见你 ♪
♪ To see you again ♪
♪ 我还是回来了  让我进去吧 ♪
♪ I'm back at your door please let me in ♪
♪ 我看到你的微笑 ♪
♪ I saw that little smile ♪
♪ 在脸上雀跃 ♪
♪ Playing on your face ♪
♪ 你早就知道我会回到你身边 ♪
♪ You knew I'd come running back to your side ♪
♪ 只要你心里 ♪
♪ But if you find it in your heart ♪
♪ 依然爱我 ♪
♪ To love me still ♪
♪ 我就不会遗憾 ♪
♪ I'll never be sorry ♪
♪ 我忘了我的骄傲 ♪
♪ I forgot about my pride ♪
♪ 我回来了  就好像我不曾离开 ♪
♪ I'm back just like I've never been away.. ♪
我有预定
I have a reservation.
-请问名字是  -贝弗·摩尔
- Can I have a name? - Bev Mole.
欢迎你  摩尔小姐
Welcome, Ms. Mole.
谢谢入住本店
Thanks for staying with us.
-开了很远车吗  -从阿贾克斯来的
- Traveling far? - Ajax.
真好
Lovely.
我要看看你的驾照
I need to see your license.
你预定了两晚
I have you staying with us for two nights
赌场欢迎你
compliments of the casino.
需要帮你搬行李吗
Can I help with your bags?
不用
No.
♪ 我回来了  就好像我不曾离开 ♪
♪ I'm back just like I've never been.. ♪
♪ 我回来了  你一定要 ♪
♪ I'm back and you gotta ♪
♪ 让我留下 ♪
♪ Let me stay ♪
♪ 尽管你警告过我 ♪
♪ Though you warned me not to try ♪
♪ 别再来你家见你 ♪
♪ To see you again ♪
♪ 我还是回来了  让我进去吧 ♪
♪ I'm back at your door please let me in ♪
你是谁
Who are you?
警察
Police.
什么
What?
警察
Police!
她锁上了  好吧
She locked it. Okay.
我一定要让你离开这
I've got, gotta get you out of here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
操  好吧
Oh, shit. Okay.
好吧  首先
Okay, first..
我要你告诉我亚历克斯·穆兰的事
...I need you to tell me about Alex Moulin.
是查理·莱克让你做的吗
Did Charles Lake send you?
我们拍了照
We took pictures.
拍立得照片
Polaroids.
拍了什么
Of what?
伤疤  他的伤疤
The scars. His scars.
你们把他弄伤了吗
Scars you gave him?
不
No.
不  他们不喜欢小孩
No, they don't like children.
-是谁不喜欢  -老虎们
- Who don't? - Tigers.
是谁
Who don't?
老虎们
Tigers.
我们只想要钱
We only wanted the money.
穆兰夫妇得为虐待他付出代价
The Moulins needed to pay for what they did to him.
他死了之后
And after he died..
我想告诉警察
...I tried to tell the police..
但我妻子
...but my wife --
-她阻止你了吗  -是的  她阻止了我
- She stopped you? - Yeah, she stopped me.
那个  那个男孩
The, the boy..
我们丢下他的时候他还很  很好
...he was f -- fine when we left him.
-丢下他吗  -是的
- Left him? - Yeah.
在哪丢下他的
Left him where?
格尔
Ger!
现在我帮不了你
I can't help you right now.
但我一定会的  我保证
But I will. I promise.
我们要走了
We're gettin' out of here.
操他妈的骗子
Fuckin' scam!
格尔  我们要走了
Ger! We're leavin'!
操
Fuck!
对不起亲爱的
Sorry, sweetness.
我知道我们刚刚才来
I know we just got here.
赌场想诱骗我
The casino tried to entrap me.
狗娘养的
Motherfuckers.
操
Fuck!
天啊
Aw, geez!
我们要离开这个该死的镇子
We're leaving this fuckin' town.
这里真他妈操蛋
What a shit hole this is.
操  走啊
Fuck! Come on.
走啊  操你妈
Come on, you fucker!
快走
Come on!
在沙漠里我看到了一个生物
In the desert I saw a creature
赤身裸体  充满兽性
naked, bestial.
她蹲在地上  手里握着她的心脏
Who, squatting on the ground, held her heart in her hands
然后吃掉了它
and ate of it!
我问  "好吃吗  朋友"
I said, "Is it good, friend?"
"它很苦  很苦"他说
"It is bitter, bitter," he answered.
"但我喜欢它  因为它很苦  很苦
"But I like it because it is bitter, bitter.
更因为它是我的心脏"
And because it is my heart."
艾比
Abby!
艾比  发生了什么  孩子
Abby, what's going on, kiddo?
我接到了查尔斯湖公司律师的电话
I got a call from the CLC lawyers.
他们要接手旅馆了  艾比
They're taking the motel, Abby.
不管你是用蜡笔  口红
It doesn't matter whether you signed it in crayon, lipstick
还是隐形墨水签字的  合同都会生效
or invisible ink, it's binding!
我已经和你妹妹谈过了
I've already talked to your sister.
老实说  她听起来如释重负
She sounded relieved, to be honest with you.
你就收下那笔钱吧  孩子
Just take the money, kid.
改善下生活
Get your life sorted.
妈妈真的想卖掉这里吗
Did mom really want to sell this place?
-艾比  -告诉我吧
- Abby..  - Just tell me.
她已经死了  告诉我吧
She's dead. Just tell me.
我只能说  这件事定下来的时候
I can tell you that once the decision was made
她很平静
she was at peace with it.
我只能说这么多
That much I can tell you.
她真美
Isn't she beautiful?
穆兰夫妇强迫亚历克斯参与演出
The Moulins were forcing Alex to be in their act.
和老虎一起
With the tigers.
但发生了可怕的意外
But there was a terrible accident
所以他们囚禁他  把他藏起来
so they locked him up and they hid him away.
但驯兽师贝弗·摩尔
But Bev Mole, the animal trainer
她是唯一知道这件事的外人
she was the only outsider who knew.
你知道这个人吗
Does that name mean anything to you?
不知道
Nope.
好吧  贝弗决定拍下浑身是伤的亚历克斯
Well, Bev decides to take pictures of a scarred-up Alex
并用照片勒索穆兰夫妇
and uses them to blackmail the Moulins.
一切都按计划进行
Everything goes according to plan
直到亚历克斯挣脱控制逃跑出来
until Alex somehow breaks free and runs away.
所以说  这一切贝弗都参与其中
So, Bev's complicit in all this
她被迫去寻找他的下落
and she's forced to track him down
并把他带回交给穆兰夫妇
and take him back to the Moulins
但之后就再没他的消息了
but then he's never heard from again.
-再见  沃尔特  -亲爱的  晚安
- Bye, Walter. - Goodnight, darlin'.
外星生物接近
Alien life-form approaching.
你想说什么
So, what are you implying?
是穆兰夫妇杀了他们的孩子
The Moulins killed their own kid.
虐待  老虎袭击  还有勒索
The abuse, the tiger attack, the blackmail --
没错  没错  没错
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
谁才是受益人
Cui prodest, right?
贝弗·摩尔和穆兰夫妇是一条绳上的蚂蚱
Bev Mole and the Moulins are bound.
而之后他们就闹僵了
It's been a cold war ever since.
我以为你是个聪明的姑娘
I thought you were a smart kid.
我以为你能看得明白
I thought your eyes were open.
"拼出真相"  就是这样啊
"Complete the picture." That's what this is.
这并不是场针对莱克家族的阴谋
It isn't some dubious campaign against the Lake family.
你以为你了解这些人
You think you know these people.
我看见你开车经过我家的汽车旅店
I've seen you driving by my motel.
四处窥探
Snooping around.
你很偏执
You're paranoid.
你说的是查尔斯湖公司集团的旅店吧
Don't you mean CLC's motel?
还是说你忘了马上要签的土地转让协议
Or maybe you just forgot to mention your pending land deal.
再见
Goodbye.
查尔斯湖公司  即将开业
我靠
Fuck!
靠
Fuck.
♪ 曾经 ♪
♪ Once ♪
♪ 我曾经拥有 ♪
♪ Once it was mine ♪
老虎袭击
♪ 如果爱是泪滴 ♪
♪ If love's a tear ♪
网页        图片          视频         新闻        地图       更多                                   工具
人被老虎
咬死
老虎袭击
为何会发生
图解
老虎袭击
警告  图片  男孩掉进老虎坑被咬
游客在狩猎时被老虎咬伤  官方称
老虎袭击  百科全书
15张老虎攻击的恐怖图片警示
妇女被老虎拖走
老虎袭击
♪ 那么我愿哭泣 ♪
♪ I want to cry ♪
♪ 如果爱有翅膀 ♪
♪ If it has wings ♪
♪ 那么我想飞翔 ♪
♪ I wanna fly ♪
♪ 我知道我永远不会 ♪
♪ I know I'd never ♪
♪ 永远不会放弃 ♪
♪ Never let go ♪
♪ 曾经 ♪
♪ Once ♪
♪ 我曾经拥有 ♪
♪ Once it was mine ♪
♪ 爱如一啜美酒 ♪
♪ It was a sip of wine ♪
♪ 我愿细细品味 ♪
♪ I want to taste it ♪
♪ 这颗心  这双唇 ♪
♪ This heart and these lips of mine ♪
♪ 不应白白辜负 ♪
♪ Don't want to be wasted ♪
♪ 如果爱是场游戏 ♪
♪ If love's a game ♪
♪ 我愿在其中嬉戏 ♪
♪ I wanna play ♪
♪ 如果爱有代价 ♪
♪ If there's a price ♪
♪ 我愿不惜一切 ♪
♪ I want to pay ♪
♪ 至少让我 ♪
♪ Let me at least.. ♪
-你今天要去哪里  -就进趟城
- Where you going today? - Just to town.
看个演出
Seeing a show.
格里森
劳雷
玩得开心
Enjoy the show.
谢谢
Thank you.
♪ 我曾经拥有 ♪
♪ Once it was mine ♪
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen!
神奇穆兰
神话还是魔法
请尽快就坐  演出即将开始
Please take your seats. The show is about to begin.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen!
卡尤加赌场很荣幸为您献上
The Cayuga Casino is proud to present
两届魔术世界冠军的表演
the two-time world champions of magic.
最令人惊叹  最不可思议  最神乎其技的
The marvelous, miraculous, magical
神奇穆兰
Magnificent Moulins!
晚上好
Bonsoir!
Good evening!
谢谢大家  欢迎你们来看我的表演
Thank you! Thank you and welcome to my show!
什么
What?
你的表演
Your show?
到底是谁的表演
Well, whose show is it?
怎么了
What is this?
出什么事了
What is going on?
我想该给这蠢货一个教训了
I think it is time to teach this animal a lesson!
你们认为呢
What do you think?
再见吧
Bye!
一  二  三
One, two, three!
神奇的赫卡
The amazing Heka!
她是不是好美
Isn't she beautiful?
她想要点掌声
She loves your applause.
她六个月大的时候我们收养了她
We adopted her when she was six months old.
她妈妈死了  只留下她自己
Her mother died, she was left all alone.
无依无靠  饥饿难耐
Abandoned. Hungry.
但她是个斗士
But she's a fighter!
是不是呀  赫卡
Isn't that true, Heka?
赫卡  你说什么
What, Heka?
我听到了吗
Did I hear that?
你想念穆兰先生吗
You miss Mr. Moulin?
她想让我把他弄回来
She wants me to bring him back.
我必须这么做吗
Do I have to?
好吧
Okay.
穆兰先生  你去哪儿了
Mr. Moulin. Where are you?
我在这儿
Here I am!
谢谢
Thank you!
谢谢你  赫卡
Thank you, Heka!
也谢谢你  我亲爱的
And thank you, my love!
谢谢你
Thank you!
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
照片
Picture?
晚安
Goodnight.
你们真是
You guys...
你过奖了
You're way too kind.
我要写给谁
Who should I make it out, too?
写给亚历克斯就好
Just make it out to Alex.
我在街对面的餐厅等你们
I'll be at the diner across the street.
♪ 你不会伤我的心吗 ♪
♪ Won't you break my heart ♪
♪ 再一次 ♪
♪ One more time ♪
♪ 你不愿吻我的唇吗 ♪
♪ Won't you kiss my lips ♪
♪ 再一次 ♪
♪ One more time ♪
♪ 当我知道将得到什么 ♪
♪ I'll be back when I know ♪
♪ 我就会回来♪
♪ What I'll find.. ♪
♪ 再一次 ♪
♪ One more time.. ♪
这里禁止吸烟
I don't think you can smoke here.
穆兰太太  来点咖啡吗
Coffee, Mrs. Moulin?
不要
No.
菜单
老虎那故事还挺感人的嘛
Touching story about the tiger.
你都快要哭了
I even saw some tears.
想象一下  如果你讲的是你过世的儿子
Imagine the reaction if you told them
他们会是什么反应
about your dead son.
♪ 我就在那儿 ♪
♪ I'll be there ♪
你们怎么弄的
How'd you do it?
25年了
It's been 25 years.
我们已经学会了适应
We've learned to adjust.
我指的是老虎那把戏
I mean, the tiger trick.
真的很壮观
It's really spectacular.
你到底想要什么
Look, what exactly do you want?
她想要钱  笨蛋
She wants money, imbecile.
她派你来的吗
She sent you?
告诉她我们不会再给她一毛钱
Tell her she won't get another grubby dime from us.
相反  我们会想办法弄死她
We've got Chernobyl of dirt on her compared to that.
-需要帮您来点什么吗  -不要  滚开
- Can I get anybody something? - No, fuck off!
那女人偷我们的东西
That woman stole from us.
勒索我们  差点毁了我们的事业
Blackmailed us, she almost ruined our careers!
更别说绑架了你们儿子
Not to mention, kidnapped your son.
不是她派你来的吗
She didn't send you?
♪ 你需要一个朋友 ♪
♪ You'll need a friend ♪
♪ 但是不会有 ♪
♪ But there won't be.. ♪
留着吧
Keep it.
我有原件
I have the originals.
多少钱
Well, how much?
我不想要钱
I don't want money.
我想知道真相
I want the truth.
真相
Truth.
你还挺聪明的  是吧
You're pretty smart, huh?
可你的所作所为真是蠢到家了
But what you're doing here is fucking dopey.
但我得承认  你做得满腔热血
But I'll admit, you do it with a certain exuberance.
别扯远
You're stalling.
-真相  -真相
- The truth. - The truth.
真相
The truth.
真相是
The truth is..
我们也不知道
...we don't know.
我们付了钱给她
We paid her the money.
约定是她带他回农场
The deal was she would take him back to the farm.
但他从未出现
But he never got there.
我们报了警  警方说他是自杀的
We went to the police. They told us he committed suicide.
他们都不听我们的话
They didn't want to listen to us!
现在  查理·莱克那只小鹰
Now, that chicken hawk Charles Lake..
试图告诉我们一个消息
...was trying to send us a message.
警察和贝弗莉那个贱人
The police and that bitch Beverly..
都在勒索名单上
...they were all on the payroll.
-什么消息  -他带走了我的孩子
- What message? - He took my boy.
我的宝贝
Mon bebe.
我的儿子
Mon petit garcon.
真相
The truth.
他就在那儿
He was there..
被绑在他的小笼子里
...tied up in his little cage.
神志不清
Half-conscious.
后来我们发现个好机会
And we saw an opportunity.
我们试着教亚历克斯  试着让他参加表演
We tried to teach Alex, tried to include him.
但是他被宠坏了  软弱无能
But he was spoiled, soft.
老虎屈服于强大
Tigers bow to strength.
而恐惧只会让他们对猎物垂涎三尺
Fear only makes them salivate.
这是他的错  而不是老虎的错
It was really his fault more than the tiger's.
可能他就是因此跌落悬崖
It could have sent him over the cliff.
摔在岩石上粉身碎骨
The body breaks up on the rocks.
倒霉孩子就该有倒霉下场
The sad child does what sad children do.
请给我来点咖啡  谢谢
I'll have some coffee please, now. Thank you.
说出来感觉还不错  是吧
Feels good to get that off our chest, doesn't it, boy?
没错
Yeah.
就是这样  真相
There you have it, the truth..
和一个谎言
...and a lie.
哪个是哪个  你来辨别吧
You have to decide which is which.
恐怕又有一番功课要做了
More homework, I'm afraid.
亲爱的  不要不好意思
Don't be embarrassed, honey.
不要
Don't.
顺便说一嘴  把戏的门道是  烟和镜子
It's smoke and mirrors, by the way, the trick.
我们在赫卡和观众之间放了一面镜子
We drop a mirror between Heka and the audience.
一点偏转
A little redirection
一点光
a little light.
去吧
Go ahead..
去告诉别人吧  看有人信你吗
...tell someone. See if they believe you.
现在  滚开
Now scram.
滚
Scram!
去往加拿大
慢点
Slow down.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
你在美国逗留了过久
How long were you in the States?
就一天
Just a day.
艾比  这个谈话纯属自愿
Abby, this is, uh, strictly voluntary.
你妹妹这次宽宏大量地
Your sister has graciously agreed
决定不追究你
to take you in for the time being.
但是我觉得你得跟她解释一下
However, I think you owe her an explanation
你拿她的护照干什么
as to what you were doing with her passport.
没事的  艾比
It's okay, Abby.
我的姐姐会周期性地干一些古怪的事
My sister has these, uh, cycles.
劳雷  你知道你姐姐在回家前
Laure, do you know what your sister was doing
都干了什么吗
before she came back home?
她提到过跟一个男朋友
She mentioned something about
在多伦多逍遥了一阵子
bumming around Toronto with a, a boyfriend
但是最后他们搞砸分手了
and fucking that all up, or..
这是什么
What is this?
这是艾比上一个"古怪周期"
That is Abby's last cycle.
在过去的十八个月里
She was in Phoenix, Arizona,
她一直在亚利桑那州凤凰城
the last eighteen months
对外声称自己有逆行性健忘症
claiming that she had retrograde amnesia.
你知道那是什么病吗
Do you know what that is?
就是在你头部受创后失去
It's when you hit your head and lose all memory
所有受伤前的记忆
of anything that happened before the injury.
她让当地人相信她真的忘了自己的身份
She convinced people she didn't know who she was.
名字  家庭  所有事
Her name, her family, anything.
人们都以为她
People thought that she'd escaped
从人贩子手里逃了出来
some human trafficking ring.
一个当地的社工还特别关注她
And then a local caseworker made Abby his pet cause
并试图让政府给她一个身份证明
trying to get the state to issue her an ID.
这在那里还引起了点轰动
It was a bit of a story down there.
媒体称她为"沙漠里的简"
The press dubbed her "Jane of the Desert."
"沙漠里的简"是个骗子
但是当她的谎言败露后
And then once she got exposed
你可以想象的各种麻烦都来了
it got pretty messy, as you can imagine.
打官司  看心理医生  吃药  被遣返
Lawyers, psychiatrists, meds. The deportation.
她被永久禁止进入美国
She was banned from ever going back into the United States.
是你的母亲救了他
And it was your mom who came to her rescue.
母亲
Mom?
-这些都是她花钱摆平的  -是的
- She -- she paid for all this?  -Yes.
她用旅馆作抵押借了一笔钱
With a loan against the sale of the motel.
为什么她不跟我说
Why didn't she tell me?
因为她怕这件事会让
Because she was afraid it was going to
你们彻底决裂
tear the two of you apart, permanently.
你母亲为此付出了巨大的代价
This had a real cost on your mom.
艾比
Abby..
你是我的姐姐
You are my sister
无论如何我都会爱你的
and I love you, despite everything.
请你看着我的眼睛
Just, just look me in the eye
告诉我你干了这些事
and tell me you did this.
我只有这一个请求
That's all.
我找到他们了  劳雷
I got them, Laure.
他们告诉我了
They told me.
谁
Who?
他们告诉了你什么
Who told you what?
穆兰夫妇
The Moulins.
艾比  别现在提起这茬儿
No, Abby, we are not, we are not doing this.
难道你现在不相信这事儿了
So you don't believe any of this now?
向我保证你会去就医
Just -- just tell me you'll get help
我会全程陪伴你
I will be there the whole way.
他们告诉了我一切
They laid it all out for me.
亚历克斯是怎么死的和为什么要杀他
They -- they told me how they killed him and why.
手法  动机  利益
It's means, motive, opportunity!
-停停停  -穆兰夫妇
- Stop it! Stop it! - The Moulins!
你一定要传唤并审问他们
You have to bring them in for questioning!
穆兰夫妇  我还以为亚历克斯是被
The Moulins? I thought Alex was -- was whacked
某个邪恶组织杀害的
by some evil consortium --
劳雷  我知道整个过程  劳雷
Laure, I -- I got the whole story, Laure!
这消息听起来很有意思
I'm sure it's very interesting.
但是它一点也经不起推敲
But it -- it just doesn't add up.
艾比  为什么你不承认你在凤凰城干了什么
Abby, why can't you just admit what you did in Phoenix?
因为我没有
Because I'm not..
因为我在保护自己
Because I was protecting myself.
我不是个骗子
I'm not a liar.
劳雷
Laure..
我真的不是
I'm not.
在我看来在这种情况下
Well, it seems to me that under the circumstances
你有权这么做
that you have a perfect right.
真的吗
You do?
我需要一个证人
Well, I wouldn't want to do it without a witness.
-我可以作证  -是吗
- Well, that's me. - It is?
那正好
Well, that's all I wanted to know.
请试着往里面看
Try and look in that thing..
尼亚加拉警察局
证人笔录
沃尔特·贝尔
不要听这个疯子的
他是个怪人  别把他说的当真
驾照
姓名:贝佛利·安妮·摩尔
地址:安省阿贾克斯镇橡树街33号L1S0B6
好的  拜拜  亲爱的
Alright. Bye, babe.
拜拜
See ya.
冷静  冷静
Calm down. Calm down.
没事的  请别慌
It's okay. Don't panic, please.
我只是想跟你说说话
I just want to talk to you.
好吧
Okay.
我想给你看点东西
And I want to show you something.
看一下这些
Look at these.
真的  求你看一看这些照片
Look.. I need you to look at these, please.
你记得那一天吗
You remember that day?
-这是我  -我不
-This is me. - I don't --
求你看一下
Look. Look, please!
你看
You see?
你记得这一天吗
You remember this day?
你想要弥补你的过错吗
You want to make it right again?
我想  但是
I do. I just..
我知道
Yeah.
我可以帮你离开这里
I can get you out of here.
但是我需要你帮我干件事
But I need you to do something for me.
好
Yeah.
你懂吗
You understand?
欢迎大家收听《瀑布之上》播客
Ndio, kwe and yineh to the "Over the Falls" podcast.
录播于尼亚加拉唯一的
Recorded live from the hangar deck of Niagara's
飞碟餐厅
only Flying Saucer.
我是沃尔特·贝尔
I'm Walter Bell. And, folks,
正如劳伦斯·威尔克所说的那样
as Lawrence Welk would say
"能来到这里  我荣幸至极"
"It's wonderful, wonderful to be here."
他妈的从我的房子滚出去
Get the fuck out of my house!
我们今天的话题很特殊
We have a very special episode for you today.
我们的老听众肯定会知道原因
Our long-time listeners will surely know why.
我20年来一直在告诉警方
For over 20 years, I've been telling the police
查尔斯·雷克二世为了保护他儿子
that Charles Lake II had Alex Moulin murdered
查尔斯湖公司现在的老板查尔斯三世
all to protect his son
让人杀了亚历克斯·穆兰
current CLC boss Charles III.
他想要保护的还有他儿子的恋童癖
And his elicit taste for young, vulnerable boys.
我们为了给这个犯罪家族带来应有的惩罚
We fought a long and bloody battle to bring retribution
进行了漫长而血腥的斗争
to this criminal clan.
今天我可以很骄傲地宣布我们获得了胜利
So, today, I'm proud to say we are on the cusp of victory.
在离多伦多市
This sleepy neighborhood in the suburban town of Ajax
45分钟车程的阿贾克斯镇上
forty-five minutes outside of Toronto
警方对我身后的这座房屋的突袭
was shaken by the sounds of a police raid
惊动了这个熟睡的街区
as officers charged into this bungalow behind me.
58岁已退休的贝弗莉·摩尔被警方逮捕
Inside, 58-year-old retiree, Beverly Mole
她涉嫌非法监禁并
was arrested for the forcible confinement
折磨她身患残疾的丈夫
and suspected torture of her physically-disabled husband.
重大新闻
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h丈夫被妻子灌药并关押数十年
但当警方询问这位
However, when police talked to the victim
51岁的受害人格里·摩尔的时候
fifty-one-year-old Gerry Mole
他透露了一个出人意料的惊人消息
he dropped a bombshell no one saw coming.
据格里所说  他的妻子在二十五年前
According to Gerry, his wife was the hired gun
受已故尼亚加拉大瀑布大亨
for a ghastly crime that took place almost 25 years ago.
对失踪男孩的搜索还在继续
雷克三世宣布查尔斯湖公司新的发展计划
重大新闻
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h已故尼亚加拉大瀑布大亨查尔斯·雷克二世
查尔斯·雷克二世的雇佣和指使
A crime she committed on behalf of the now-deceased
犯下了一起惊人罪案
Niagara Falls tycoon Charles Lake II.
这起案件直到今天
A crime that, until now
才浮出水面
wasn't even a crime at all.
谁能想到年轻的亚历克斯会遭此不幸
Who could have fathomed such a fate for young Alex?
被他的父母折磨  被一个怪人猥亵
Tortured by his parents, defiled by a deviant
然后像举行仪式一样被喂给了一笼子老虎
then fed to a den of tigers like some ritual slaughter.
这真的是败类中的极品
Truly, this was a masterpiece of degeneracy.
我们对他被虐待并不知情
We did not know about the abuse.
更不知道他被谋杀
We certainly did not know about his murder.
我们会与这个恶意诽谤斗到底
We intend to fight this gross, malicious slander.
有一个人名叫沃尔特·贝尔的人愿意
Someone who was willing to comment was this man
就此事发表评论
Walter Bell
他作为水下救援队"贝尔潜游一族"
who many in the region would recognize as a member of
的一员在当地以胆大而闻名
the local daredevil and water rescue team, The Diving Bells.
沃尔特是最初搜索队的一员
Walter was a part of the original search-party
他负责在尼亚加拉河里搜索打捞
that scoured the Niagara River for any evidence
亚历克斯·穆兰的遗体
of Alex Moulin's remains.
据沃尔特所说  事情看起来并不太对劲
According to Walter, something seemed off immediately.
亚历克斯当然不是第一个受害人
Of course, Alex wasn't the first.
我们看到的只是冰山一角
We've only started to scratch the surface on the story
相信我
believe me.
我有一个播客
Uh, I also have a podcast.
叫《瀑布之上》
It's called "Over the Falls."
当我们等待调查重启结果的时候
As we await the outcome of this re-opened investigation
听众们要牢记我们为了正义同任人唯亲
I remind my listeners of our long fight for justice
笑里藏刀和暴力杀戮进行的长期斗争
against nepotism, beguiling iniquity and bloodshed.
致所有收听播客的人
To everyone that stuck with us
恶人会自食恶果
thus always to tyrants.
新闻标题  查理·莱克否认对他的指控
有什么可以帮你的吗
Can I help you?
有
Yeah.
还有房间吗
You have a room?
住几晚
How many nights?
还不知道
Uh, don't know yet.
有空房  我需要你的驾照
I have a room. I just need your driver's license
和信用卡
and credit card.
我只有现金
Yeah. Um, I only have cash.
好的
Okay.
那你有没有身份证件
Do you have any ID?
加拿大英属哥伦比亚省
姓名  亚力克·穆林恩
-多少钱  -一百块钱押金
- How much? - A hundred-dollar deposit.
温哥华
Vancouver.
是
Yeah.
离家够远的
It's a long way from home.
第一次来尼亚加拉大瀑布吗
First time in Niagara Falls?
很久以来的第一次
First time in a long time.
是什么让你回来的
What brings you back?
我们认识吗
Do we know each other?
不
No.
你知道吗
You know..
他没在说谎
...he's not lying.
他从来没有伤害那个孩子吗
He never hurt that kid?
没有
No.
他救了他一命
Saved his life.
那是我的吗
That mine?
是的
Oh, yeah.
谢谢你  艾比
Thanks, Abby.